(What an Unexpected Moment in My Life)
Nice to see you all!
It's been a long time, Ji Hyeon.
- It's been a while. - It's nice to see you.
- It's nice to see you. - We last saw him on the field day.
- Right. - That's right.
- Have you been well? - I've been working hard.
- Wait. Did you perform at an event? - Oh, my.
- Well, today... - Look at your outfit.
- You're dressed in Western clothes. - You're wearing a suit.
Oh, my.
This man in high spirits,
Ji Hyeon, has spent a day with a special someone.
Let's watch the footage to find out who it is.
(With a Special Someone)
(Ji Hyeon is heading somewhere while humming a song.)
(Smiling)
Seoul Express Bus Terminal.
- A bus terminal? - That's a bus terminal.
(Seoul Express Bus Terminal)
(Surprised)
This place is nice.
Christmas is nearing.
- It's already the end of the year. - Christmas is nearing already?
My gosh, it will soon be Christmas.
(Buses and people are moving busily at the terminal.)
There it is.
There it is. I'm here.
(It's a package collection point from express buses.)
My octopuses are transported...
- on express buses these days. - That's right.
- You always use that service. - Yes.
- That's the fastest service. - Yes.
Hello.
(He meticulously fills out the registration form.)
- Hello. - Hello.
So you're the recipient.
- There are two packages. - Yes.
- Give it to the worker. - Okay.
Your packages are outside.
- Okay. Thank you. - Bye.
- Who sent you the packages? - My mother did.
- From Mokpo? - Yes.
- These two packages are yours. - Okay.
(Lifting)
I didn't know about this service.
- That's the fastest. - It arrives on the same day.
That's the best way to get fresh seafood, right?
- They'd still be alive. - Yes. When I worked in Mokpo,
I used to send the packages through express buses...
for customers who wanted their seafood fresh.
So you used to do that.
Wait, that's different from a courier service?
- It's not. - It's the same-day...
- delivery. - The same-day delivery.
They just send the packages via bus.
- Right. - They can send only the packages?
- Yes. - They can.
My gosh.
(The boxes arrive by bus with the food still fresh.)
They're heavy.
Park Ji Hyeon.
- Hello. - Gosh, the ladies.
You're beautiful.
- They clapped to greet him. - Thank you.
Hello.
(Like a friendly guy, he smiles back at them.)
(He exits the terminal in a good mood.)
Gosh, they're heavy.
(He loads the boxes into his car.)
What? Did you buy a car?
It's a rental.
- It's a rental? - I see.
They're precious packages.
I wanted to transport them safely to my house.
How precious could they be...
- that you rented a car? - You rented a car for them?
My gosh, look at the fall foliage.
(He sets out on a drive with precious packages.)
The autumn leaves look beautiful.
Autumn leaves.
It's the Han River.
(He continues to hum melodically.)
I can tell you're excited.
Are you going somewhere?
- I had to do something. - I see.
There's a series of speed bumps ahead.
(I'm here.)
My gosh.
(He comes back home while carrying the boxes.)
- Your house looks quite neat. - Right?
Right? That thing is gone.
- Hey, why is your house so clean? - Where are the humidifiers?
(With a big humidifier in the middle of the living room,)
(his house looked a bit chaotic.)
Yes. You got rid of everything.
I needed the counter for something since a few days ago.
- I had to clear the counter first. - You needed a lot of space?
- Yes. - I see.
What?
She sent me a knife too.
- A knife? Oh, my. - My gosh.
- Gosh, that's a sashimi knife. - It's a sashimi knife.
My mother sent it to me because she wanted me to cut it nicely.
Looking at your suit and the knife you're holding...
- Right. - You could be...
- in a noir film. - Right.
- "Sunflower." - That's right.
"Just spend three years in there."
"This is great weather to slice sashimi."
We might hear him sing "Wild Bee."
He's good at cutting seafood.
He used to work in that field.
Yes. He looks professional.
(Rummaging through)
(Fresh octopus from Mokpo)
- The three-legged ones? - Yes.
- Aren't they expensive? - Yes, they are.
- They're so expensive now. - She sent me a lot of abalones.
- Oh, my. Look how big they are. - Abalones.
- Are they from Wan Island? - Yes.
Okay. I got this.
If he's preparing fresh seafood, this someone must be very special.
It could be his teacher.
(As soon as he opens them up, he calls someone.)
- Hello. - Hello.
Hey.
- Mom. - What are you doing?
- Yes. - I got the boxes.
- You did? - Yes.
Why did you send me salted shrimp?
It's more fermented than I expected.
When did you get this?
I fermented it for about a week.
It must weigh around 5kg.
Yes. About that much.
Okay then.
- Is that a skate? - Yes.
A skate? Gosh.
(He has brought a whole skate from his hometown, Mokpo.)
(He will prepare the fish in his house in Seoul.)
It's quite fermented.
(Massive)
(Grabbing powerfully)
To cook for someone really important,
I got a lot of ingredients.
He's a great senior singer who represents my hometown.
He's the pride of Mokpo.
He's the best singer...
- Is it who I think it is? - in our industry.
It's Nam Jin.
- My dear, Nam Jin. - He will be on our show?
Yes, Nam Jin.
Gosh, he debuted in 1965.
- He's Elvis Presley of Korea. - He's just amazing.
- He's so cool. - He's really cool.
("Empty Glass," released in 1982)
- "Empty Glass" was great. - Look at that gaze! Oh, my.
("Nam Jin Receives Silver Crown Order of Cultural Merit")
("Nam Jin Still Influential as Ever, Receives Achievement Award")
(An all-time legendary singer celebrating his 60th anniversary)
- The 60th anniversary. - The 60th anniversary.
(The biggest role model of Ji Hyeon who often sings his songs at home)
- He's the sexiest man at that age. - Truly.
The term, "teto-man," went viral lately.
He's the very first teto-man.
- He's a real man. - He's so manly.
- Yes. - Totally.
Personally, I'm a huge fan.
- Me too. - "I'm a man." When he sings that,
- it gives me so much energy. - Yes.
Just watching him is enough.
- Right. - I can feel his energy.
Wait. I've met him once.
"Radio Star."
- You filmed with him? - Yes.
I met him in front of the bathroom and said, "It's an honor, sir."
- My stage name is difficult. - Yes.
- He asked, "What was it?" - I said, "CODE..."
- He said, "So you're a Ko?" - Okay.
He told me I could tease him however much I wanted.
- Right. - Yes.
- He says that. - He told me to treat him...
any other guest.
Then he told me about how he got stabbed.
(Then he told me about how he got stabbed.)
He told you a very important story.
That's an important story.
- You're dressed like him today. - Yes.
(Ji Hyeon is dressed just like him today.)
- He likes three-piece suits. - Respect.
- He always wears rings. - He likes wearing rings.
- Gemstone rings? - He likes fancy accessories.
Getting punched with that will hurt.
I contacted him during the holidays.
So I couldn't see him in person because of our schedules.
Then he invited me to come over.
But I can't show up empty-handed.
I can't go and order food...
- from a delivery app. - Right.
To show him how much I respect him,
the only thing I could think of was to bring the food with me.
It will be like a royal meal...
- for a king. - My gosh. Yes.
That's great.
He's an important part of my life.
He means a lot to me.
(To cook for someone he treasures...)
I put my heart into it.
- You look great as a court maid. - You look great.
- You look beautiful. - I did my best.
- Hey, they put effort into the CGI. - Hey, you look so pretty.
I wanted him to have a taste of home.
The packages had a skate, octopuses,
abalones, and salted fish.
That's it.
I'm not cooking for myself. It's for my VIP.
I made an effort to clean the kitchen.
I wanted to cook for him and didn't want anything...
to be a problem.
Isn't it his 60th anniversary...
- this year? - It is.
- This is quite meaningful then. - Yes.
A junior singer whose role model is him...
- is cooking for him. - Right.
They're from the same hometown.
Then is he 80 years old?
- He's older than 80. - He's 81.
- Our age difference is 50 years. - He's amazing.
- Isn't it exactly 50? - Yes.
He was born in 1945, and I was born in 1995.
- He was born in 1945? - Yes.
- He experienced the Korean War. - Right.
- He fought in the Vietnam War. - The Vietnam War.
He's the living history.
(He's indeed the living history of Korea.)
I don't have a big cutting board.
(He washes the cutting board and puts it down.)
I tried to keep it clean.
(He gets ready to cook in a clean environment for Nam Jin.)
- You want this to be a treat. - Yes.
(Let me start.)
(Chopping)
- Gosh, he's so good at this. - Oh, my.
- He has the best knife skills. - It's "Culinary Class Wars."
(With his knife skill, it looks like a cooking competition.)
He's good.
(Chopping furiously)
To cook for someone really important to me...
(He's chopping it wholeheartedly.)
It's fun to watch him cook.
He's good at cooking.
He's like a professional. So it's fun to watch him cook.
You finely chopped the vegetables.
Abalones are fresh.
The abalones are huge.
Doesn't it feel nice?
(Shucking the shell)
He's good.
(He prepares the abalones without any problem.)
- What's that? - The innards of the abalones.
(Grabbing something)
(A mortar suddenly shows up.)
(Pouring the innards)
Into the mortar?
(Circling)
That's the origin of mortars.
I don't have a blender.
Using that is the authentic way.
I ran everything in my head the day before.
My gosh. Look at the color.
It shows that he has experience.
When you cook, you're not pretentious. I love that.
- Who's pretentious when they cook? - What would be pretentious cooking?
- I think I know what you mean. - Yes. Right?
I know someone who overuses fancy tools.
Who's that pretentious jerk?
Who's that jerk?
(I'm famous for having tools.)
That startled me.
It's not hot at all.
(Cooking is also all about looking cool for Moomoo.)
It's about the tools.
- Right. - Exactly.
- Tools aren't important. - They're not.
- Ji Hyeon doesn't show off at all. - People should keep that in mind.
- Exactly. - He's super cool.
"He's super cool."
(Chuckling bitterly)
(Putting down the pot in a super cool manner)
I guess he's going to cook porridge.
- That's right. - I see.
(He tastes the abalone porridge with innards.)
(Okay. I just have to boil this now.)
Oh, no. My cutting board is too small.
The cutting board is too small.
He's being pretentious.
That's cute.
- He's just excited. - What's wrong with him?
- I was just excited. - Yes.
(He excitedly makes sure it's clean for Nam Jin.)
It's been a while.
Mr. Kim Skate.
Are you fermented nicely?
(Yes)
My gosh. How are you going to cut that?
- The cutting board is too small. - Yes. I didn't think about that.
(It's bigger than the cutting board.)
(Royal Meal from Mokpo for Someone Special)
(A week-fermented skate)
Oh, my. It really has been a while.
(My knife is going in now.)
(Slicing)
(Putting it down)
(He starts with the middle part.)
- He's separating the liver. - My gosh.
- Oh, my. - That's the liver.
The gallbladder is in the middle.
If you pop it while cutting the fish,
- the fish gets covered in that. - You can't use the fish then.
- Right. It's bitter then. - I see.
My hands seem to remember what to do.
That's the meat from the tail.
Why did you put them in separate bowls?
I separate the innards, bones, and flesh.
- I use them separately. - I see.
This must be completely different...
- from regular fish. - Right.
Preparing skate is such a big challenge.
You need to execute that step well.
Your knife must follow the bones next to the gill to cut it neatly.
(Chopping)
He's good.
That's how a professional does it.
- The wings. - Oh, my.
(Cracking)
- You're really good at this. - Yes.
- That's a skill too. - What are you doing?
That's the cheek.
The cheek meat is a rare cut.
You don't hesitate at all.
(He continues on.)
- He's really good. - He's so good.
That's where the mouth is. I cut the gill in half.
Here's the thing with the gills.
You must rinse them thoroughly with water.
- Otherwise, they'd stink a lot. - I see.
Is it like having a bad breath?
Yes, it's something like that.
- They breathe through that. - Right.
(Splitting the gill open in half)
My gosh.
It's been three years.
I was 23 years old when I cut my 1st skate.
That's when I started working.
Then I worked until I was 29.
- I cut at least 30 skate every day. - My gosh.
He said 30 skate every day.
I did that for seven years.
So 300 working days in 1 year...
Three times seven is twenty-one.
So for 2,100 days...
I cut 30 skate every day for 2,100 days.
Oh, my.
Two times three is six.
- So it's around 60,000. - I cut 6,300 skate.
(He cut 6,300 skate in 7 years?)
Is that right? Is it 6,300 skate?
- Isn't it around 60,000 skate? - Isn't it 60,000 skate?
It's 63,000?
Gosh, 63,000 skate?
(Shocked)
Gosh, see? He's not showing off.
He didn't calculate it until now.
- He's good. - That's being genuine.
So many chefs these days aren't genuine.
- Like who? - Who do you mean?
Never mind.
He always looks at me then.
No. Well, you happen to be there.
(A certain someone who often uses fancy tools)
(He cuts the skate genuinely from the bottom of his heart.)
(He uses his hand to pull it.)
- He's peeling off the skin. - My gosh.
(He tugs the skin to peel it.)
(Slicing it once)
My gosh.
He's amazing.
I can't believe he's doing that at home.
Do you want to compete in "Culinary Class Wars?"
No.
(He also removes pieces of skin on the fish.)
(Only the skin is removed, without a piece of flesh.)
It's like he's at a sashimi restaurant.
(He grabs something.)
The thawing sheets.
Gosh, you used thawing sheets too?
I call the process sweating out the fish.
When the fish is wrapped up like that briefly,
- Right. - it's chewier.
Sweating out the fish.
(Grabbing)
(For his senior singer who debuted 50 years before him,)
(he will dust off his skills from the old days.)
(Chopping)
My gosh. That looks tasty.
(Cutting a slice of skate)
(Tasting)
(It's good.)
(Cutting it for the satisfying crunch)
Is it supposed to be crunchy?
- Yes. - Yes. It has bones inside.
That looks great.
(Opening)
(He puts on gloves in the middle of cooking.)
(The snout is the finale.)
Look at that.
(As it's slippery, he puts on gloves.)
(The snout of the skate)
Gosh, that's the stinkiest part.
There are different groups for skate eaters.
- Groups that eat snouts and don't. - Right.
Right. I want to put some aged kimchi on that.
(Next up is a halved chunk of meat.)
(Adding the whole chunk into the pot)
He's making suyuk.
- For the skate combo. - Yes.
- He must prepare the skate combo. - Yes.
Oh, my.
(He even brings out beef.)
Is it for beef radish soup?
- Okay. - I see.
He's making radish soup.
He makes it look so easy.
Okay.
Come here.
- Thanks for making the long trip. - Octopus.
Oh, my.
Thank you for coming all the way here.
It will be a stamina-boosting meal.
(He acquires only the delicacies like skate, beef, and octopus.)
I don't want this to choke him.
Chopped raw octopus?
- Yes. He must chop that. - All right.
What's that?
(Sizzling)
Gosh, you're cooking the live octopus?
(He'll stir-fry this precious live octopus?)
- You'll stir-fry the live octopus? - Yes.
Now, you're just showing off.
I added abalones to the stir-fried octopus too.
My gosh. That's a top-quality dish.
How many dishes is he cooking simultaneously?
I cooked 6 to 7 dishes.
He's being really generous.
All right. Come here, suyuk.
(Let me check on the suyuk.)
Is it cooked or what?
(The knife goes easily into the meat.)
(It's cooked perfectly.)
(Adding to the insulated container)
- He's doing a great job. - That's great.
He's good at adding the food into that tiny box.
(Opening)
(Aged kimchi for the suyuk)
- It's aged kimchi. - Oh, dear. It's aged kimchi.
(Whining)
(Stained with the sauce)
(I should wipe it off before he tastes it.)
(Suyuk and kimchi, the perfect combo for skate)
(Thick abalone porridge with innards)
You used insulated containers...
- for everything. - Yes.
It was quite far.
Right. Temperature is important in cooking.
Especially so for elders.
Their food must be nice and warm.
- Right. - Temperature is important.
(Refreshing beef radish soup)
(Salted octopus, a representative side dish of Mokpo)
Salted hairtail intestines look so tasty!
(Nam Jin's favorite dish, green onion kimchi)
- That's a lot of love. - You prepared all this for him?
It will take me about eight hours to prepare this dish.
How long did it take to cook everything?
I could've finished sooner.
I also had to pack up the food.
- It took about two hours. - Gosh!
- He cooks really fast. - That's really fast.
He broke down the skate...
- from scratch. - Right.
- He's really good. - He's fast.
Right.
(Thinking)
(It's missing something.)
(Figs?)
- They're figs. - Figs.
I had them before.
- We tried them before. - They were so good.
(He brought figs on Innocent Moo-Ku Fall Field Day.)
(His figs won over the hearts of the members at once.)
- They were so sweet. - They were so good.
- Figs are the best. - They were different...
from the ones I was used to.
- Right? They're fuller inside. - They tasted different.
- Right. - Yes.
(He inspects and picks out only the pretty ones.)
(Carefully rinsing them)
How beautiful.
Did you pick out only the best ones?
- Right. Yes, only the pretty ones. - Only the pretty ones?
- Not the popped ones, right? - Right.
(A complete royal meal with a dessert)
All done.
(A generous amount of food)
(He opens up the cabinet again when he's done preparing the food.)
- What's that? A wrapper too? - You're going to wrap them up?
Rock-wrapper-scissors.
I thought I misheard you.
That's so cute.
(What was that?)
Gosh, he's Ji Hyeon's fan.
- He's good. - Of course.
(Laying out)
It's like a carpet.
Food tastes good when it's packed like that.
- Right? It has that vibe too. - Yes.
(He packs a feast with respect...)
(for a senior who is 50 years older than hin.)
(He ties it prettily.)
(The colorful packaging is complete.)
It's time to wash up.
(Getting ready to meet Nam Jin)
(Feeling refreshed, he goes to the closet.)
I prepared an outfit like this.
I had it ready the day before.
You're putting in more effort than you do for a blind date.
Nam Jin is like that.
(Sniffing)
(He even check the smell reverently.)
What time is it?
It's a pretty outfit.
It's my first time seeing Ji Hyeon...
in his own clothes.
(He makes himself look polished.)
(He shakes his hair.)
(Then he moistens his lips.)
(Grinning)
(He walks out with a big package.)
(It's time to see the recipient of the packed food.)
(Feeling nervous, he scratches the back of his head.)
Turn on Bluetooth.
(The familiar intro echoes in the car.)
"A Nest."
("A Nest" by Nam Jin)
(We shouldn't wander anymore)
(Cheering)
(He sings to soothe his nervous heart.)
(I wouldn't have looked at the ferry with an aching heart)
(Impressed)
You memorized all the lyrics.
Of course.
("Heartbreakingly" by Nam Jin)
(Time, don't hasten yourself)
What's that song?
It's "Resume."
("Resume" by Nam Jin)
(I still have it.)
(Meow)
(At this moment, I'm Nam Jin.)
(My goodness)
All the songs by Nam Jin are cool.
(The sun sets as he sings...)
(a medley of Nam Jin's songs.)
(I wail)
- Gosh, there's a traffic jam. - There's a traffic jam.
(The traffic jam makes him wail.)
My goodness.
(Feeling nervous, he becomes one with the wheel.)
My nervousness intensified...
because the trip was so long.
- Of course. I bet you felt anxious. - A short trip is better.
That's better. It's better to get there fast.
That's right.
The food shouldn't go cold.
How far are you going?
I'm traveling from Gangseo-gu to Gwangjin-gu.
- One end to the other. - The traffic jam is crazy there.
Those neighborhoods are the two opposite ends.
- Two hours aren't much. - It's so far.
Please let the food be tasty.
Please let him enjoy the food.
(Traveling across Seoul feels longer than a trip to Mokpo.)
I'm here.
(Is it this place?)
(Feeling nervous, he enters the building.)
(Let's see.)
(Sighing)
You had met him a few times.
- I had met him a few times, - It's different.
but it was my first time saying hello to him properly.
- It was the first private meeting. - Yes.
I bet it was nerve-racking.
Of course, it was nerve-racking.
(Ji Hyeon steps inside carefully.)
(Peeking)
(Bowing)
Hello.
It makes sense.
- I can hear his voice. - It makes sense.
(His silhouette can be seen.)
(As you get closer,)
(his sense of presence becomes heavier.)
Okay. All right.
(He halts at the door.)
- Hello. - Hello.
Hey.
- So, - Yes?
- is everything going well? - Everything is going well.
(The living legend of the music industry, Nam Jin)
(So, is everything going well?)
I'm in the middle of a meeting, so I'll join you soon.
- Okay. - All right.
- What are those big packages? - Oh, these are...
- I'll show you later. - My goodness.
I'm curious. All right.
I'll be at the back.
- Okay. See you later. - Okay.
Okay.
- He has a sense of presence. - He's cool.
This is Nam Jin's office.
(Happy)
A person who doesn't know Nam Jin in Korea...
has to be a spy...
- They have to be a spy. - or a foreigner.
I met him for the first time on a music show.
Although I was a junior singer who had just debuted...
I said, "Nam Jin, hello."
I wanted to tell him that I had always respected him.
But as soon as I said hello,
he went, "Are you from Mokpo?"
I was so surprised. I was like, "How does he know that?"
- Seriously. - He knows everything.
Seriously, you've become successful.
My nickname used to be At-Home Nam Jin.
I've become someone...
who has a private meeting with Nam Jin.
(At-Home Nam Jin waits for his senior singer.)
(Polite)
He became a little kid.
(Staring)
(He puts down the containers gently.)
(Feeling like a student, he straightens his clothes.)
He seems like a student.
I was really nervous.
(He waits in an extremely nervous state.)
I don't remember that time.
My goodness.
- Nam Jin, hello. - My goodness.
- I was in the middle of a meeting. - Okay.
- It's good to see you. - Okay.
- He's so homely. - We didn't even get to talk.
- Have you been well? - Yes, I've been well.
- Is everything going well? - Yes.
You're fairly tall.
- "Fairly." - "Fairly."
- Have you been well? - Of course. It's all thanks to you.
- I've been hearing about you. - Thank you.
He doesn't seem like someone in his 80s.
How does he live so young?
You're right. He looks the same.
He seriously looks the same.
- He doesn't get old. - He looks like he's in his 60s.
I asked him if I could call him...
- "Big brother." - You could call him that.
"You should call me 'Big brother.'"
You could call him that.
He'll always be a big brother.
It's good to see you today.
- I've been wanting to meet you. - I know.
- I... - You brought something nice.
- For you, - Okay.
I brought some food.
- You brought tasty food. - Yes, I brought tasty food.
I'm a bit excited.
I cooked diligently.
I've heard about your cooking skills.
Really?
I've heard a lot about them.
- Really? - Yes.
- All right. Shall we go over there? - I cooked diligently.
- Okay. Over there. - Over there.
- Over there. - Sir.
- Ji Hyeon's face turned red. - There's a kitchen.
- I bet you don't remember that. - I really don't.
I was really nervous.
My hands were shaking. Seriously.
Sir, if you sit comfortably,
- I'll prepare the food in no time. - Shall I sit here?
You can sit anywhere you want.
Shall I do that?
(He's happy to see a friendly junior singer.)
Sir, I heard...
- that you liked skate. - Of course.
He's quaking.
- Back in the day... - Skate is a dish...
- that represents Jeolla Province. - You're right.
I was...
- in the skate industry. - So I heard.
I brought various things.
(Struggling)
Here.
This is... I brought a lot.
- Speak louder. - I was nervous.
Hey, you were intimidated.
- It can't be helped. - It can't be helped.
- Oh, no. - He's the oldest senior...
among active singers.
On top of that, I'm also in the trot scene.
He's a direct senior.
Even when he puts me at ease, I feel scared.
Having respect makes you nervous.
- This is... - Is it a seasoned dish?
This one is salted fish gut and this one is salted octopus.
Tasty salted seafood is a must in the Jeolla Province cuisine.
Yes.
A meal doesn't taste good if the salted seafood is bad.
(Oh, no)
What's that? It looks like skate.
It's like "Culinary Class Wars."
Are you getting judged?
It was nerve-racking.
That's right.
I prepared the skate myself.
Isn't this that thing?
- It's the snout. - Snout.
Skate snout is the best.
It's the most flavorful.
That's the Mokpo jelly.
This is the cheek.
The rest come from fins.
I see.
I made some suyuk.
You know,
skate should be eaten with pork.
Yes.
- That's right. - Thank you.
He'll give you a pass or a fail...
or put you on hold.
(Smiling)
My goodness.
You brought so much tasty food.
I prepared it myself since this morning.
You have the right attitude.
You know how to respect your senior.
- Yes. - That's the spirit of Mokpo.
- That's right. - I couldn't come...
- empty-handed to see you. - You're too kind.
Ji Hyeon, you have the right attitude.
Thank you.
A handsome man...
with a bad attitude is no good.
He could untie it easily earlier. But it isn't working now.
You have the right attitude.
- Thank you. - You're good.
I'm working hard to follow your footsteps.
What did he say? I couldn't hear him.
Speak clearly.
I know how he feels, so I'm getting even more nervous.
- It was so nerve-racking. - You're doing great.
I packed it here so that it'd remain warm.
I made it this morning.
- That's beef radish soup. - This is beef radish soup.
There are so many kinds of food.
(Grabbing)
All right.
- You should eat as well. - Okay. I'll sit and eat as well.
Let's eat together.
Food doesn't taste good when you eat alone.
- And this is abalone porridge. - What's that?
- Abalone porridge. - Abalone porridge.
- I used the guts as well. - I see. Abalone porridge.
- Abalone guts. - It looks tasty.
Guts are important.
Oh, my. Ever since you were little, you've been involved...
with the food service industry.
Yes, I ran a fish store.
That's why you're different.
- This is what you like. - Green onion kimchi?
- Yes. - That's right.
I know that you like green onion kimchi.
My mom sent me green onion kimchi all the way to Vietnam.
- What? - My goodness.
Green onion kimchi reminds me of my mom.
- Really? - Yes.
(I'm glad I brought it.)
What? Aren't those figs?
- Yes, I brought figs. - They grow in Mokpo and Yeongam.
I brought them from Yeongam.
He brought Mokpo to Nam Jin.
(Proud)
Gosh, I should give a prayer of gratitude.
You brought tasty food.
It's a meal from Mokpo.
Well done.
Shall I try this?
- Stir it well. - Okay.
(Slurping)
How is it?
I can see that he's nervous.
Maybe he'll say, "It's salty.
(Joking)
- His lips are the color of skate. - Skate.
He has aged.
Since he was used to eating tasty food,
- I didn't know if he'd like it. - He travels around Korea..
and eats all sorts of delicacies.
If it suits his taste...
(Nervous)
It's a shame that I'm eating this alone.
- Thank goodness. - Really?
Of course. It isn't easy...
to eat such tasty food.
Really? I'm glad.
Look at the octopus.
I like small octopuses.
- Yes. - Big ones taste bad.
I'm glad to hear that.
Big octopuses aren't available these days.
- Big ones taste bad. - Okay.
- They're called sil octopuses. - Okay.
- Sibal octopuses. - Okay.
- He means, "Three-legged." - Three-legged octopuses.
- He pronounced it as "Sibal." - Mokpo residents say, "Sibal."
- "Sibal." - Old people call them...
- "Sibal octopuses." - That's right.
(Impressed)
He's eating it with gusto.
Look at the skate. My goodness.
The meat is like a glutinous rice cake.
- He loves it. - He loves it very much.
- Soy sauce? - There's chojang.
Oh, my.
Haven't you eaten?
- Me? - Haven't you eaten?
I skipped a meal because I wanted to eat a lot of this.
That's right.
You're used to cooking.
He loves it.
- Let's eat together. - Okay.
I didn't bring a separate bowl.
All done.
- He left it behind. - He left it behind.
- Oh, no. - It happens when you're busy.
May I eat it out of your bowl?
Of course. People who get along...
- can eat out of the same bowl. - Okay.
- Go ahead and eat. - Thank you.
All right. They're a family.
(Upon hearing Nam Jin's suggestion, he takes the first bite.)
My goodness.
- You couldn't taste it, right? - Yes. Seriously.
By the way, I really wanted to meet you.
I wanted to meet you over a long period of time.
We always crossed paths.
We never got to talk properly.
I heard about you,
but I didn't have a lot of time.
Thank you so much for calling me over...
today.
Thank you for bringing tasty food.
You have the right attitude.
Whenever you call me,
I'll bring tasty food.
I've brought my juniors...
to nice restaurants...
and paid for meals.
But I've never prepared dishes from Jeolla Province.
It's the very first time someone has done this for me.
- Oh, my. - Such an occasion is rare.
- Don't change. - Okay.
- Bring food again. - Okay.
When did you start singing?
In middle school,
I dreamed of becoming a dance singer.
You dreamed of becoming a dance singer.
Back in my days, not a single singer...
danced while singing.
(He shocked the Korean music industry...)
(as the master of performances.)
(His specialty was the pelvic dance.)
That was when you became interested.
That's right.
- Sir, I have a question. - Okay.
You've been active for over 60 years.
Exactly 60 years.
Weren't there any struggles?
I had many struggles.
- I fought in the Vietnam War. - I know that very well.
- Back then, you were... - I was very popular.
very popular.
Have you ever come close to dying?
No.
It's a true story.
- It's a true story. - Seriously.
I was about to go outside after eating a meal...
when I heard a whooshing sound.
Everyone fell.
I was like, "What?"
It was a bomb that hadn't gone off.
It had a propeller at the back.
It was spinning like this.
It was right next to me. I was so surprised.
- Had it gone off... - You would've died or...
- I would've died. - Did it fall right next to him?
He survived because it didn't go off.
There was another story I heard.
- Was there another story? - He was sleeping...
when someone stabbed his pillow.
- He was attacked. - He was attacked. Yes.
A story of getting attacked. Yes.
- A robber entered. - A robber entered.
I heard that story on my very first major show.
Gosh, I see.
I bet you thought, "So, major shows are like this."
I thought "Show Me the Money" was better.
Listen. You guys have diss battles, but he had actual battles.
(I respect him.)
That's the real hip-hop.
- Seriously. - The real hip-hop.
(Pushing)
- Have some figs. - Figs.
Figs remind me of my childhood.
Modern figs are different from the old Mokpo figs.
- That's the same variety. - Right?
- I can tell. - I see.
- These are the old figs. - You're right.
- Modern figs aren't full. - That's right.
I don't eat them even if they're free.
- They're really tasty. - Yes.
These figs are very tasty.
(They become absorbed in the Mokpo figs.)
They were so tasty.
(My goodness)
(Eating)
(Nam Jin even loves the dessert.)
Sir, I have a question.
I can't imagine working actively as a singer for 60 years.
Have you ever wanted to quit?
- I never thought about quitting. - Really?
I only thought about working harder.
(Impressed)
He's so incredible.
Why do you think I was able to work for 60 years?
It's because I had many great songs.
Singers disappear after 2 to 3 years without them.
After me came...
Hoon A and Yong Pil.
(My goodness)
It was the age of romance.
Ji Hyeon,
you need to have your unique colors.
You need to develop the aspects you like.
How else would you get connections?
That's how you get connected to people.
You know the saying. Seven parts luck, three parts talent.
You need luck.
You need to have luck on your side.
You should've written it down.
Those were some wise words.
When we sing, we go, "Your love..."
We can always use that.
"A Nest" goes,
"Bam, bam, bam, bam, bam."
(He sings to teach a junior singer who comes 50 years behind him.)
(He even drums the table.)
That's how the song goes.
- It's a very expensive lesson. - That's right.
- Where else will you hear it? - That's right.
You should listen to pansori.
- It helps a lot. - Okay.
I hope you'll follow in my footsteps.
Nam Jin's pick.
Yes.
I heard that you sang my songs on the stage.
- I sing them diligently. - I haven't been able to watch them.
I want to watch them.
What's your style?
- It'll be nice to watch. - Let's go.
That's right.
- Let's go. - He wants to watch.
- Let's go. - Yes.
It's a good opportunity.
It'll be nice to watch.
I did it at a concert.
(Would you like to watch a video from my concert?)
(Curious)
This is...
But I haven't been able to sing properly.
- Since I had sung multiple songs, - In the beginning of your career,
- I didn't sing the last song well. - it's natural to mess up.
It'd be unnatural to sing perfectly.
(It's time to show the result of his practice!)
"A Nest" was the last song.
(My goodness)
- It must be nerve-racking. - I'd be nervous too.
(Watching carefully)
There's a dolphin inside.
Gosh!
- Gosh. - That's intimidating.
(Focused)
(Breathless with nervousness)
There's a part that pays homage to your motion as well.
I see.
- I'm feeling nervous. - This is scary.
(Let's see it.)
I added in your move.
(Flashy dancing skills)
He's laughing.
(Nam Jin's signature moves)
- Blue looks good on him. - Right.
(He feel proud of his junior's dance moves.)
I changed the choreography...
a bit like that.
You're very talented.
Based on your body type and physique,
you're a singer who must dance.
I'll root for you.
Thank you so much.
Add in the Mokpo Dance.
- The Mokpo Dance? - The Mokpo Dance?
What could that be?
Your moves are the Mokpo Dance.
Well, actually,
I've always imagined...
doing a duet with you.
That was why you went.
- Gosh! - That's not true!
- But you have to make those moves. - Really?
You have to make yourself known.
I'm not asking you right now for a duet,
but there are some lyrics that I wrote...
while imagining doing a duet with you.
Right. Let's see them.
- Bring them over. - That's great.
I've been writing a lot of lyrics these days.
- Is that so? - I've been writing a lot.
- I came up with them briefly. - Right.
- Well... - This never happened.
It's important to be different.
I don't think I remember seeing a men's duet.
May I read the lyrics to you?
Sure.
I'm quite lacking now,
but I wrote those lyrics while dreaming of that day.
That must be really embarrassing.
Go on.
First of all,
the title is "Eighty-One, Thirty-One."
- It was made with him in mind. - Right.
- The first verse is your part. - Right.
(Ready to listen)
"I'm no longer ambitious now."
"I've done all I can."
"Passionate love, loyal friendship,"
"and wandering about immaturely."
"I want to lie on that vast beach."
(I want to lie on that vast beach)
- The second verse. - Right.
"I'm still full of ambition."
"I like dancing and having fun."
"I love my friends."
"I want to run around that vast beach."
"Gosh, I will run like crazy."
(Gosh, I will run like crazy.)
(Embarrassed)
(How were my lyrics?)
He doesn't look so happy.
His face stiffened.
Your part might be what he has in his heart.
(I want to run around that vast beach.)
He's still young in heart!
"You should stop now and get some rest."
"Why must I be lying around on the beach?"
- Why make him like that? - "I still want to be in love."
- Gosh. - "I'm still young in heart."
That wasn't my intention. I wanted to write lyrics...
about a senior in life.
What makes him more like a senior...
is for the one that is 81...
to sing that he still is ambitious at that age.
- That's a lot more impressive. - It's better to switch it around.
- Right. That's a great idea. - That's great.
(Feeling proud)
Make sure to make a lot of changes to the lyrics.
Right. I will have to.
(What will Jin think?)
- That's great. - Right.
It feels passionate and realistic.
Were you always talented in writing?
- Were you into writing in school? - Well, no.
I was never into writing.
You must've read a lot of books.
- I've only read one book. - Right.
"So that explains."
"No wonder."
"Right. No wonder."
- "I see. Read some books." - "I see now."
"That explains everything."
I'm the worst when it comes to writing.
- Why would you say that? - No. I'm serious.
I haven't read a lot of books.
- I've only read one. - Right.
You've read one book, at least. I haven't read a single book.
You're better than me.
He didn't say anything about doing a duet though.
To me, Nam Jin...
feels like a reliable tree that has been around for a while.
Just like he is right now,
no matter how many years pass by,
I wish for him to be happy...
and healthy for a long time.
I just wish him to be healthy.
(A strong pillar that kept him dreaming)
A brother forever, and our Nam Jin forever.
That is what my heart wishes him to be.
(My Idol and Strong Pillar Forever)
(I Live Alone)
(Bok Has Come)
(Groaning)
There's so much extra space on the bed.
Right.
Gosh, my shoulder hurts.
My shoulder hurts a lot as I have to use a lot of my forearm.
You're using your forearm these days?
(What time is it?)
(Getting up)
(She gets up right away without any hesitation.)
I got up early in the morning.
I usually never wake up at that time.
(She moves quickly in the morning on her day off.)
Bokdol!
Did you sleep well?
(There's a dog in Na Rae's house?)
I am Park Na Rae, who doesn't live alone anymore.
- This is Bokdol. - Gosh!
It's a male dog that is five.
He's my new pet friend.
- Gosh! - He's smiling!
Bokdol loves smiling.
- He's adorable. - The dog has a smiley face.
(During dinner at Na Rae's grandparents' house...)
(when the three were there to clear up the place)
(There's a Jindo dog that my grandfather raised.)
(His name is Bokdol.)
(The dog was sent to the hospital for a health check.)
(After my grandfather passed away,)
(I kept thinking about Bokdol.)
(Don't worry and raise him. I'll help you.)
(I think Bokdol will bring a lot of good things to you.)
The two of them strongly recommended...
that I should raise Bokdol.
That was why I made that big decision.
"I'll take him home tomorrow."
It has been around two months and a half...
since I've lived with Bokdol.
- He's so cute! - He looks handsome.
- It's a brindle. - Right.
I'm a total rookie when it comes to raising dogs.
Him and I are both...
are trying our best to adjust to each other.
- I need your help as my seniors. - Right.
I've asked everyone around me including Ki Bum.
- Please help me. - Of course.
- There's Lee Jung as well. - I will definitely help.
Everyone except for President Jun...
has a pet cat...
- or a pet dog. - Right.
(Butlers and cat experts)
I'm also a dog expert.
- Really? - But I had to send mine away.
(Pookie)
Right. You've lived with your dog for a long time.
I've lived with my dog for a long time.
(Feeling grateful)
As for Bokdol,
he's quite small for a Jindo dog.
He's like the small giant of Jindo dogs like Park Na Rae.
This is who Park Bokdol is.
- Dogs take after their owners. - He's a small giant.
- You two were destined to meet. - He's a bit small.
- You love the leopard print. - I absolutely do.
What a match.
- That's why I love him even more. - He's just like his owner.
(They are just like each other with their fancy looks.)
He loves people...
and has great memory.
He remembers every single person just after seeing them once.
He's adorable.
(Eyes full of love)
(For this cute and small giant,)
(Na Rae made a place for him on the 1st floor.)
I can't believe I'm seeing this at Na Rae's house.
Right.
Who would've expected to see that at my house?
(There are dog items all around the house.)
This is a great place for Bokdol.
(Na Rae's house has changed for Bokdol.)
Bokdol!
(Laughing)
You're so excited.
(Excited)
Gosh, what is going on?
(She opens the fence while greeting him in the morning.)
Come out, Bokdol.
(Rushing out)
- How exciting! - Gosh.
He's so cute!
Come here.
You're so adorable.
(She gives him a morning pat with all of her care.)
Isn't this really nice?
You have a presence to look for...
- right after waking up. - Right.
- You're greeted in the morning. - Right.
I've been with them every single day for 13 years,
but they greet me every single morning.
Right.
They wag their tails like crazy.
It feels really weird to me.
- Right? - It's because...
Bokdol and I...
started living together right after our blind date.
- Right. - It must feel like a dating show.
It does feel like a dating show.
The house feels like one from a dating show as well.
Totally.
(We've started living together right from the start.)
(Park Na Rae, 40, comedienne)
(Bokdol, 5, home protector)
We're slowly adjusting to each other at our own pace.
I won't try to rush things.
Right.
Bokdol, go out and poop.
Go out and poop.
Does he only poop outside?
He pees on the dog pad...
and poops outside.
- I see. He's a smart dog. - I see.
What is all this? What a mess.
A total mess.
- Gosh! - It's a total mess.
- It's a flood. - I got so surprised.
- Right. - Right.
(She gets the cleaning tools first.)
Gosh.
(She soaks it up with the dog pad first.)
When you raise a dog,
you have to start the day by cleaning that up.
The dog pad has to be cleaned up.
Na Rae is in our world now.
(A familiar sight)
(She wipes the floor cleanly.)
(There we go.)
Done.
The dog pad is huge.
It's big enough for a person to use.
(Feeling proud)
(She heads outside after placing the large dog pad.)
Where did you poop, Bokdol?
(It's over there.)
Where? Did you poop there?
(He leads the way after smartly understanding her.)
(Disgusted)
- Bokdol! - What's wrong?
- My goodness. - Gosh.
Good job!
(Good job, my Bokdol.)
Good job.
(Unlike Bokdol who is excited after getting complimented...)
- He's excited. - He's totally excited.
Good job.
(Closing her eyes)
Gosh, it's warm.
It's warm when you touch it at that moment.
(That warmth is hard to get used to even after many times.)
It's massive in size with big dogs.
Doing things a regular basis and following a routine?
I'm someone who never does that.
But there was a change after meeting him.
Just for Bokdol,
there are things I have to do...
- in the morning. - Right.
It has become a routine.
Those are things you must do.
I get up early now.
(Thank you, Na Rae.)
(While Bokdol is running around,)
(she gets out dried pollack.)
As he's a dog from Mokpo,
he likes fish more than meat.
- Gosh. - Gosh.
She's preparing a meal for the dog before her own meal.
Gosh!
(She quickly washes even the sweet potato.)
(Bokdol's breakfast is prepared in a hurry.)
(She comes out to the living room while the sweet potato cooks.)
Bokdol?
Bokdol.
He knows his name.
He comes when I call his name around five times.
Should we eat now?
Should we eat? Let's eat.
This is your favorite, dried pollack.
Do you want some dried pollack?
- Wait here. - He's excited.
Don't come up.
- So he's not allowed to go up. - Really?
- This is our rule. - You're doing great.
I have a lot of guests that come over...
and my house has...
- so many different things. - Right.
There's food and dangerous objects.
That is why I limited his space to the first floor.
That makes sense.
(Only Na Rae goes up as they keep their own rule.)
(He follows Na Rae.)
(He stops right in front of the staircase.)
I made it certain. That is how we can live together!
I said that, but...
He must be really hungry.
No, Bokdol!
We promised each other that you won't come up, Bokdol.
You remember our rule, don't you?
You're a bad dog if you come up.
I'm sorry.
(I'm sorry for sending you away.)
- Bokdol. - He listens well though.
He listens well.
You're a bad dog if you come up.
Bokdol is a bad dog.
He's a bad boy.
You're a bad dog if you come up.
He still goes back down.
(Whining)
You're a bad dog if you come up. Come here.
You look excited.
(Slowly moving over)
(Where is he going?)
You look excited.
- He's so curious. - He must want to go up.
Bokdol!
(He keeps going up the stairs.)
It's hard to tell if he's going to listen or not.
It's hard to communicate as a dog and an owner.
Stay inside for just a while.
The ultimate treat.
You will have to follow this.
I'll feed you if you stay inside for just a while.
I should go in first.
Come here.
Stay here for just a while.
(She manages to bring him in with the treat.)
Good job.
I'm sorry. Stay in there for just a while.
He can definitely go over the sofa, but he won't do that.
He never jumps over the sofa.
- He's smart. - He's smart.
(She returns to the kitchen after dealing with the situation.)
(She checks Bokdol's sweet potato.)
(Has it cooked well?)
Gosh, that's hot.
(The sweet potato was cooked just right.)
That's hot.
- So much care is put in. - Exactly.
- Dogs can't have hot things. - Right.
(Shaking)
- What are you adding in? - What is that?
- Is that a supplement? - He needs to take his medicine.
(Bokdol's medicine is added to Bokdol's favorite dried pollack.)
(Pouring)
(The cooled-down sweet potato is added as the finishing touch.)
(Sweating)
(Bokdol's special meal full of care is complete.)
How many meals is that for?
Does he eat that much for a single meal?
- It's for a single meal. - Gosh.
Isn't that too high in calories?
You have to feed him that much?
I was told he had to put on some weight.
That was why I cut up everything for him including the dried pollack.
He did put on some weight. He gained 2kg in a month and a half.
- His weight must be taken care of. - He must feel happy there...
as he gained weight.
That's a relief.
Bokdol.
Dried pollack?
(The dog from Mokpo gets excited after seeing the dried pollack.)
Gosh, you're so excited!
Have some water. Here.
The dog that loves dried pollack. Here you are.
(Eating)
Eat slowly.
Look at that.
- Gosh, he's eating well. - He's eating well.
He eats it so well.
Is it that good? There you go.
(He enjoys Na Rae's special meal.)
It feels great when the dog eats well, right?
- Right. - He eats well.
That's the best feeling.
(He eats for a while with his nose in the bowl.)
Let's see how much you have eaten.
Why did you leave the sweet potato? You ate all of the dried pollack.
Will you not finish the sweet potato?
He's definitely from Mokpo.
What a good dog. You ate well.
(Feeling drowsy)
- He must feel great. - Right.
(She returns to the kitchen after proudly feeding Bokdol.)
I don't know if I should eat or not.
It's like childrearing.
- Right. - Once I feed him,
- I'm completely exhausted. - Right.
(Rustling)
Low-sugar matcha.
(Let's eat lightly since I'm exhausted.)
I'm a true matcha lover.
Matcha lover.
(She prepares her meal after taking care of Bokdol.)
That's such a simple meal.
My life has become simple.
(Her breakfast was prepared in a flash.)
- You placed my paintings there. - Right.
That was the perfect spot.
I always see them there when I eat.
(Poking)
(She takes a big bite of the matcha rice cake.)
The matcha tastes rich.
(She enjoys a short break with the rice cake.)
(Satisfied)
There's so much filling inside.
This is the best in the morning.
(Eating)
You must eat your breakfast a lot simpler now.
I couldn't be bothered to do things now.
(I couldn't be bothered.)
That is why rookie parents don't eat well.
Right.
(The rookie dog owner moved busily early in the morning.)
Gosh.
(Her whole body aches.)
(She cleans up right away even though her body aches.)
Gosh, he didn't finish the sweet potato.
(She takes care of the leftovers.)
Well, someone has to take care of it.
I'll go and take a nap.
Right. Let's have some alone time.
(She goes back to her bed.)
As you got up too early?
I had to feed him.
I can't feed him at the time I usually wake up.
That is why I go back to sleep after feeding him.
You go back to sleep after doing everything?
Yes.
It's the same routine over and over.
(Groaning)
Gosh, I'm tired.
(Drowsy)
(She wakes up for the second time while struggling.)
- It's time to feed Bokdol lunch. - Right.
- You're the dog's mother. - Right.
- You then sleep again. - Right.
- And dinner is next. - Run the vacuum cleaner.
You're living a simpler life than a dog's life.
- The dog is busier. - Right.
Bokdol?
Gosh!
(Smiling)
Did you get some rest?
Did you get some rest, sir?
(Reuniting with Bokdol as soon as she gets up)
Bokdol, did you get some rest?
How adorable.
You're so adorable.
- He likes that. - He does?
- Gosh. - He's like a cat.
- Oh, my. He's so cute. - That's amazing.
He doesn't even bark.
He doesn't like playing tug also.
But why doesn't he do it?
- I tried, - Yes.
- but because he's never done it... - It's because he's not used to it.
Maybe he finds toys boring.
He probably caught rats.
Should I have given him rats?
Right? Because...
he could've played more fiercely in the countryside.
The toy doesn't move around.
You should let loose a few rats, then.
I should let loose a few rats at home?
(Kian84's solution)
Bokdol.
Shall we wear new clothes?
Do you want a necklace?
Okay? Hold on a second.
Bokdol, stay still. Wait.
Wait.
Good job.
I just said he did well from my perspective.
- He likes it. - Yes.
Bokdol, were you waiting?
Goodness. Here we go.
- He should be complimented. - You should compliment him.
- You need to reward him a lot. - Yes, you need to reward him now.
Bokdol.
(Since he did well, I should reward him.)
Bokdol, shall we put this on?
Shall we put this on?
That's what you do when you first get a dog.
What do you think?
A cynical man in Itaewon.
(Not interested)
He doesn't like it.
Goodness, that boy.
Now that Bokdol is living...
in Itaewon, which is right in the middle of Seoul,
I'd like it...
- if he becomes stylish. - He's handsome.
Yes.
(The fashionista dogs are just as stylish as their owners.)
They're so cute!
Yes, just like that.
Zero.
I was hoping Bokdol would be reborn.
Yes! He should dress this fancy.
I bought a lot of clothes for him.
Maybe he can fit your clothes.
Roughly, yes.
I think he can do it.
(If it's my Bokdol, he's more than capable.)
(I'll make you a stylish dog!)
Let me see. How pretty!
Let me see.
You're a flower dog.
- How cute! - Oh, my. He's so cute.
He's happy.
Come here.
(Let's try this one on.)
- Come here. - Because he's from the country,
I got him a kimchi-making vest.
Put your feet in.
Put your feet in like this. There you go.
(Trying hard)
(Struggling)
You shouldn't do that.
- I didn't know how to put it in. - You shouldn't do that.
Dogs have a nail here too.
If you pull his foot like a human,
it could get stuck and hurt him.
So you should bend his foot and put it through the hole like this.
- This is so nice. - It's like a chicken wing and cute.
I didn't know.
Put your feet in like this.
There you go. Like this.
He doesn't whine...
- even if I touch his feet. - He's gentle.
He could growl when you do that.
He didn't growl at all.
(So far, these fashionista dogs...)
(were super prickly.)
I almost lost my right hand then.
(Dizzying)
It went through.
He's so kind. He doesn't growl even when she touches his feet.
There you go.
Bokdol, you're so cute.
Why can't you move, though?
(Standing awkwardly)
Because he's not used to it.
- He's broken. - Look at his legs.
(Bokdol is broken for real.)
They're all like that at first.
He's so cute.
(Even his tail is drooping.)
Oh, no.
Is it uncomfortable?
- Of course it is. - He's awkward.
Is he uncomfortable?
(His reaction is confusing.)
You saw the vest at Grandma's place.
You look like you are at Grandma's place.
You saw it a lot at Grandpa's place, right?
Grandma used to wear this.
He's so cute.
That's why I got you this.
It's so cute.
- He's gentle. - Goodness.
- My goodness. - He brushes his head against you.
I really can't figure you out.
Bokdol.
I have no idea...
- what he's thinking. - Of course not.
It's been two months.
I once did this during those two months.
I drank, and I was so upset.
I held Bokdol and cried for an hour.
- Goodness. - "What should we do?"
It's not that he doesn't listen to you.
It's not.
- I don't know how to feed him. - Of course.
I cried too.
I had this thought a lot when I first brought in Chacha.
Chacha cried every day for over a month.
So I thought, "Maybe I shouldn't have brought it in."
Of course not.
- "Should it live here?" - You have such thoughts.
- That's natural. - If he can be happy...
- But in the end... - But suddenly, it becomes happy.
- Yes, it just needs time. - All of a sudden.
- You should give it a lot of time. - Yes, it hasn't been that long.
That's how everyone becomes a pet owner.
- Right. You learn things like that. - That's right.
- Nothing is easy. - Of course.
Let me take it off for you.
There you go. Paw.
Give me your paw. There you go.
I took it off for you.
Well done!
(Pouring out)
- Here you go. - You're giving too much.
That's too much.
Look. It's a lot.
(Drooling)
Bokdol. Come here.
Bokdol. Sit.
Sit.
- Yes! - There you go!
- He knows how to sit now. - Okay.
There you go. Good job.
Good job. You're so smart.
There you go. You're a good dog. Don't eat too much.
Just a little bit.
There you go! Wait. You waited.
I don't think he did.
No, he did. He waited for two seconds.
It looks like he gained a bit of weight.
(Did he gain weight through this?)
(Patting)
Hold on. Bokdol.
Bokdol, wait.
(Is someone visiting the Park siblings?)
Bokdol.
Bokdol, wait.
Wait.
If you come up, you're a bad doggie.
Bokdol.
He comes up when you show your back.
Why wouldn't you listen?
Gosh, this won't do.
(She gets the door first.)
- Hold on a second. - Hello.
He came up until here. One second.
He usually doesn't come up.
No! Bokdol!
- You! - Gosh.
I knew you'd be scolded by the trainer.
Gosh, I'm sorry, ma'am.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Put him down. - "Trainer?"
You got caught while trying to escape, Bokdol.
Why did you want to leave?
You reorganized the furniture?
They're trainers who are training Bokdol.
Hyun Moo introduced the center owner to me.
(They met through the dog daycare.)
- You remember her, right? - The trainer from then.
I shared the difficulties I had while taking care of Bokdol.
He introduced her to me.
Actually, I was going to send him to the training center,
but he was too weak.
So I decided to invite the trainers to my home...
since this is where he's going to stay.
I decided to train him here.
They come once a week. This is the third session.
Gosh, seriously.
- Why do you look so concerned? - Hello.
Why do you look so concerned?
This is what I was most worried about.
When he first came to my place,
he didn't know where he was,
so he sat in front of the gate.
- At one point, - Once he got used to it?
he tried to bolt out of the gate.
- He thinks he's adapted. - He could get hit by a car.
And I'm really scared of that.
There are cars too.
What if I lose him?
You should just move to your grandmother's place.
Me?
- It's better to move there. - Everything is so extreme with you.
Should I move to Grandma's place?
Then he'll be like, "Itaewon was a good place."
That's right.
You shouldn't be someone...
- who does everything for him. - That's right.
All right.
There are so many treats up there.
Let's remove all the treats to somewhere you can't see.
There are too many treats.
(Removing the treats right away)
(Anxious)
- Now... - Oh, no.
- Did you always leave them out? - Yes.
- I'm confiscating everything. - It's amazing...
he didn't break anything when the treats were out.
I know. He's gentle, to begin with.
(You weren't giving it to me?)
It's a bolt out of the blue for him.
(His treats can be seen everywhere in the house.)
We'll just place dog-walking accessories on the counter.
Don't give him treats...
unless you're training him or giving him medicine.
Can't I give one in the morning when I wake up?
Why should you?
Because he slept well.
Okay, I won't give him any.
The treats will be given through you only.
(Na Rae will control all the treats.)
Even when guests come over, don't let them give him treats.
I told you earlier. You need to be strict when needed.
- It'll be really hard. - But...
- I can't be. - You need to. Push and pull.
- That's... - Push and pull.
If that was possible, I'd be married by now.
How can you put it like that?
That's what I'm worst at.
- Push and pull is... - I'm worst at that.
not that hard.
You shouldn't tailor everything to him and lower yourself for him.
In a way, you could've taken his time...
to look at you.
Because you shower him with love.
He's capable of focusing on you,
but you could've taken that chance away.
Also, the owner must be happy for the dog to be happy too.
You should never be held back by your dog.
Okay.
Gosh, I need to change my life values.
I'm so used to getting held back.
I'd give away everything.
- And be rejected. - We get to learn about your life.
I'm especially weak with younger men.
I've never received anything like this from a man.
It's so...
(Younger men always made Na Rae cry.)
CODE KUNST, you're a bad man.
You're a bad man. You made a woman cry.
She cried to eat the pasta.
No. What are you talking about? Why would I cry for the pasta?
- Let's not do that anymore. - Okay.
Let's make him come to you.
All my life,
I've never done push and pull.
I've only pulled.
I've kept pulling only.
I've never pushed.
To think I have to do push and pull with a dog...
What do I do?
I can't even do it with humans.
Gosh. All right.
See? How can I do push and pull with him?
You are still...
a bit anxious.
- Yes. - She is anxious,
but it's so similar to her dating style.
- You're only nice to him. - You're right.
- Yes. - Then what should I do?
I think you should be less interested.
You need to make him...
- rely on you completely. - That's right.
- But you just give everything, - Yes.
- so you're a pushover to him. - That's true.
- You don't have a status. - That's right.
It's like watching a parent deeply invested in their child's education.
That's right. It's because...
- you pamper him. - Sending him to a good school.
Kids who get pampered aren't nice to their mothers later.
- That's right. - Why...
They'll only be nice to their girlfriends when they grow up.
- That's right. - CODE KUNST, how could you?
- They don't listen to their moms. - That's right.
They only get mad because their mothers are easy.
- That's right. - "What have you ever done for me?"
(Feeling guilty)
Then the mothers will be, "What more can I do?"
(You must've heard that often.)
- What should I do now? - All right.
Now, we need to use the power of treats...
because he loves treats.
Put all these treats in your pocket.
You have the treats,
and she has an empty bowl.
Bokdol will get the treat only when he goes to you.
All right. Sit down.
You should come here too.
Bokdol.
That's fascinating.
I'm not tempting him with treats.
We're training him to come to me with my voice only.
Bokdol.
So your position will be higher than the treats.
- That's right. - Yes.
(Will it be treats or Na Rae?)
(Which will Bokdol choose?)
(Bokdol?)
Bokdol.
- "Good job." Give him a treat. - Goodness.
Good job. There you go.
Move to another spot, Na Rae.
Trainer, move to another spot too.
Bokdol.
(Clattering)
(Gosh, isn't that my bowl?)
Na Rae, call him.
Bokdol.
There's no treat when someone else calls him.
(He comes close to Na Rae again.)
- Goodness. Good job. - All right.
- No, don't touch him. - No?
Push and pull!
- All right. - Give him a treat only.
It could be a similar stimulation for Bokdol.
But only his owner gets a chance to reward him.
Oh, it's gaslighting?
- In a good way. - Yes, in a good way.
Let's try that a few more times.
This will turn into play.
(Sitting in a corner like they're playing hide-and-seek)
Bokdol.
- "Good job." - Good job.
- It looks like it's working. - Yes, it is.
- Right? - It works now.
(Sitting here and there without a break)
Bokdol.
- Must you sit like that? - Yes, I had to.
- It's hot, right? - Yes.
She's sweating.
(Pitiful)
Maybe he won't listen to you if you don't sit like that.
Bokdol.
(You're sitting there.)
Bokdol?
You should crouch down with your back against him...
even when you're outside.
- Bokdol. - He'll only look for your back.
- Bokdol. - You did it for quite a long time.
- We did it for an hour. - Well done. Good job.
- You did it for a long time. - I don't know...
if I'm training him or myself.
(Sweaty)
- Say, "Good job." - Good job.
You did well today.
It's to make him come to you when you call...
even if you don't have treats.
For that to happen, you need to repeat this a lot.
It's not easy.
It certainly is not.
- We'll get going now. - Okay.
Bokdol. Stay here for a second.
(Na Rae came out after getting changed?)
What is this now?
Bokdol, shall we go for a walk?
I'll open it for you.
- He likes it. - Let's go.
- He knows what walking is. - I'll open the door for you.
Dogs know you're going out...
- when you get changed. - Let's go.
- Dudu knows. - I see.
I need to pack for walking.
(Feeling the best)
They go ecstatic when you pack things.
(Getting ready to walk Bokdol even though she's tired)
Wet wipes...
and poop bag.
And my bullets.
(Getting lots of treats)
My flower dog.
Come here.
Let's put this on before we leave.
- There you go. - He's so gentle.
How cute!
Bokdol. You're so cute.
You're so cute, Bokdol.
I look like a helicopter mom.
Bokdol.
Let's go. Let's go out.
(Helicopter sister goes for a walk as soon as the training is over.)
(Bokdol goes ahead as he's excited.)
He walks well.
(The dog from Mokpo is excited with the smell of Seoul.)
Bokdol.
Let's go use the stairs.
(Hesitating)
- They're scared of that at first. - Let's use the stairs.
Bokdol, let's go up.
- Bokdol, come up. - But he uses the stairs at home.
- He can't use different stairs. - I know.
(Hiding behind Na Rae as he's scared)
Come up.
Bokdol. Look.
(Na Rae calmly waits for him.)
Come up.
(Trust me and come up.)
There you go! Good job.
Good job.
Good job. Bokdol.
(Bokdol has become a lot braver.)
(Since he did a good job, he gets a treat right away.)
- How cute. - You're awesome.
He's lucky when it comes to food.
There you go!
(Surprised)
There you go! Good job.
- Goodness. - Look at you.
(My baby is so brave.)
Bokdol. Good job.
You did well.
Those who have dogs say, "There you go" a lot.
- We do. "There you go. Good job." - That's right.
I have a friend who moved to Canada,
and their dog knows "There you go" in Korean.
A Canadian dog?
- "There you go." - "There you go."
- Because they say it a lot. - "There you go."
He couldn't climb up those stairs the day before.
So I carried him.
(A genius dog who overcame the unfriendly stairs in a day)
(They keep walking excitedly.)
All right.
There you go.
(The helicopter sister bombards him with compliments.)
- Why do you like grass so much? - My dogs do too.
Dogs love grass.
(Na Rae, hurry up.)
He loves all the grass in the neighborhood.
Why does he like it so much?
(I want to understand you.)
(Sniffing)
- I was curious. - He likes this smell?
(Releasing a waterfall on top of Na Rae's scent)
Dog marking.
All right.
Please hold.
There you go.
Gosh, how cute.
There you go. You're doing so well.
(She's proud of everything he does.)
(Startled)
You're scared of people.
You're scared of cars.
There are barely any cars near Grandma's place.
So he's scared of roads.
(Patting)
Let's go.
Let's hurry up and cross.
- Goodness. - You're doing so well.
Where shall we go?
This way? Okay, let's go this way.
(Namsan Seoul Tower)
Gosh, you went to a good place.
This is the best spot.
(A place where various kinds of dogs gather)
(A place where dogs socialize)
I should have a dog gathering someday.
- I know. - It's so cool.
(Getting dragged)
Do you want to run?
Shall we run?
(If Bokdol wants to run...)
Let's run.
Run!
(Bokdol runs excitedly.)
- He runs well. - Let's run. There you go.
Gosh. Slow down.
Come here.
Let's drink water.
It's tiring, right?
Bokdol, it's tiring.
(Smiling)
I think you need to drink water.
That's right. I was tired.
I don't have strength.
Bokdol.
Have some water.
That's a bowl for makgeolli, right?
- I'll give you water. - He only drinks water...
from a wide bowl.
Bokdol is used to that.
(Lapping up)
What is it? Water. Drink water.
Bokdol, water.
Come here. Have water.
If he's really thirsty, he'll drink on his own.
- Is that so? - Have water.
Have water. You don't want it?
You don't want it?
(Why won't he drink water?)
(Throwing the water out and resuming walking)
Slow down. Go slowly.
No. Oh, my.
No.
- It's him. No. - My goodness.
(Moving up and down)
No. You're scared.
- Bokdol, come here. - No, he doesn't seem scared.
Really?
You're scared. It's okay.
I'm here. Come here.
Look how fast your heart is beating.
Oh, my.
- I think you are scared. - You're scared.
Yes, I was scared. You're right.
All right. Let's go.
(Sweating profusely)
You'd lose weight.
- I did. - Exactly.
I did lose some weight.
(He's just bright.)
No. You can't.
Stay here.
(Trying her best to protect him)
- Is someone coming? - Stay with me.
- It's coming. - A big dog is coming.
- It's not big. - No.
What is it? Oh, there's a dog?
(Trotting)
Bokdol, that dog is four times smaller than you.
It's not scary. You brat, you're such a scaredy-cat.
What do we do?
Look. You're so scared.
- I think he's curious. - It's okay.
I don't think you need to...
- block him that much. - Let's go.
Is that so? Did I get too ahead?
I feel like you're rather making him mad.
You tell him to hold it,
- "What's wrong with her?" - so he gets mad.
- "Let go of me!" - Oh, no.
He won't go if you let go.
That's right.
Let's go. Let's go home and rest.
You stayed out for quite a long time.
I walked for an hour.
Bokdol, stay here for a second.
(They came home after walking.)
Hold on. We need to wipe your feet.
Come here.
Good work.
I'll remove this.
You can't eat it anymore.
Sweet potatoes, dried pollack.
You're banned.
(Removing it right away as she learned)
(Disappointed)
Get some rest. You should rest, and so should I.
Gosh, I'm starved.
It was 4pm.
All I had before that were two pieces of rice cake.
You must be starving.
She only had two pieces of rice cake.
(Let me see. This...)
It's Bokdol's favorite, dried pollack.
(I should eat it.)
- You're eating it? - She's eating it herself?
She told me not to feed him,
so I have to finish it.
- Only you can cook like that. - That's right.
If it was someone else, they'd have ordered in.
He smelled it.
(Pouring an abundant amount of perilla oil)
(Pouring water...)
(and adding an egg)
(Dried pollack soup is ready in no time.)
It's the simplest meal I've seen from you.
It really was simple.
One might think you're on a diet.
(While Bokdol is resting)
(I should eat it quickly.)
(Taking a bite of the steaming dried pollack soup)
Dried pollack is delicious.
No wonder he loves it.
(No wonder Bokdol loves it.)
(Eating in a hurry)
(It feels like her fatigue is washed away.)
(Slurping)
(This time, with kimchi on top)
It must be so good.
(Getting ready)
I just ate it even if it burned my throat.
Because you were hungry.
It looks like a mother eating what her child left.
Yes, like the kid's leftovers.
(Eating in a hurry after taking care of her child)
(Bokdol's sister eats the dried pollack instead of him)
I bought so much dried pollack, though.
This is bad.
(Slurping)
(Munching)
(With worries,)
(she drinks it from the bowl with her spoon down.)
(I can finally breathe.)
Oh, right. Sweet potatoes.
You're going to eat that too?
(Peeling a sweet potato with care)
(Tapping)
Bokdol.
Give sweet potatoes only when you give him medicine.
Gosh, it's hot. It must be good, right?
Yes. Let's eat.
Goodness. You're eating so well.
Yes, eat up.
(Na Rae watches Bokdol until the end so he has his medicine.)
I don't have any more.
It feels like I got a friend...
who will trust me until the end. I felt really good.
We're not super close yet,
but we have a great chance of becoming close friends.
She's amazing.
(Bokdol and me)
We're at a stage where we...
learn about each other little by little.
The things Bokdol's never done and what I've never done.
We'll make good memories,
and I feel like...
the days we'll share together will be fun.
I think he's the same as me.
I sprawl on the floor like this when I'm drunk.
We're the same.
Look.
I thought it was a human.
That's when you're lying on the grass.
- Gosh, look at him. - He sleeps well.
He does sleep well.
- He let his guard down. - He's hardly wary now.
Let's live well together in our house.
(Bokdol, let's live well together in our house.)
In any case,
you should consider this place your home.
(Bokdol, this is your home now.)
Itaewon is your home now.
Who knew a dog would live in that house?
I became really stable.
Let's show Grandma and Grandpa that we're living well together.
(Let's show Grandma and Grandpa that we're living well together.)
Okay?
(It's a Little Rough, but It's Okay)
How cute.
(Next story)
(Sung Hwan's eyes are filled with love.)
(Kkotbun is right by his side as always.)
(Looking at each other with affection)
(Therapeutic walking time)
(This is the park Sung Hwan and Kkotbun come often.)
(I'm excited!)
(Gosh, you look like a dog I'd grow fond of.)
(Who are you?)
(Kissing)
(Sung Hwan, what about me?)
(Sung Hwan is absorbed in new dogs.)
(She looks super angry from behind.)
(Trying her best to look away)
(But you're the best, Kkotbun.)
(The person he met after soothing Kkotbun)
(It's Ju Seung's mother?)
(Ju Seung's mother has taken good care of Sung Hwan.)
(She prepared a gift for him as expected.)
(Thank you so much, Mom.)
(And one by one, people gather.)
(The precious friends he got to meet thanks to Ju Seung)
(Chatting happily and cozily)
(Look at Sung Hwan carefully.)
(To the mother, Sung Hwan is incredibly cute.)
(Everything else goes along well except for your eyes.)
(Gosh, Mom)
(Is there ramyeon that ladies like?)
(You're the one who wants to eat it!)
(Don't get cute with me.)
Open wide, Mom.
(We're Like Family)
(I'm a fan of yours!)
(His popularity is increasing a great deal these days.)
(The appearance of a new market prince?)
(Hello, I've been living alone for 9 years.)
Hello, I'm Actor Seo Bum June.
(He's super gentle at home.)
(Today's a day off.)
(Having a half cheat day after a long time)
(It's a half cheat day because I don't eat...)
(that much.)
(Having a sandwich in the morning as soon as he wakes up)
(It was the perfect menu for a day off.)
(Bread is my life.)
(He starts his cheat day in earnest.)
(He's the rising star in the bread eating show scene.)
Sit.
(Stop eating.)
(Monde, shall we go for a walk?)
(Enjoying his holiday refreshingly)
(Shall we run excitedly?)
Let's go.
(What's wrong?)
Monde, hold on.
(I haven't had a day off in a while, but today isn't any easier.)
(He ends up running while walking his dog.)
(It May Not Be Perfect, But It's the Taste of a Day Off)